MD NAYEEM REZA

OBJECTIVE

A Fullstack Software Engineer who loves to write code and has almost 3 years of professional experience. Solving a really impactful problem is what I look for to offer the best version of myself. Keen eye to the user's experience helps me to develop better user facing products. Values and growth are the key subjects that I really care about. Learning new things and adapting with new conditions are the super powers of mine.

PERSONAL DATA

PLACE AND DATE OF BIRTH: Brahmanbaria, Bangladesh | $7^{th}April$, 1994

CURRENT ADDRESS: 47/E, West Rajabazar, Indira Road, Tejgaon, Dhaka - 1215

PHONE: (+880) 1726106981

EMAIL: reza.uranium@gmail.com
BLOG: www.uraniumreza.me
GITHUB: github.com/uraniumreza
LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/mdnayeemreza

EDUCATION

Feb 2013 - Sep 2018 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering
Dhaka, Bangladesh BANGLADESH UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING & TECHNOLOGY (BUET)

WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2019 - Present Dhaka, Bangladesh

Fullstack Javascript Engineer at ShopUp

ShopUp (a Sequoia Capital and Omidyar Network backed startup), is a marketplace for online and offline merchants to help them sell on social channels. Here, I'm working as a fullstack engineer. My main role is to work on the growth of ShopUp Reseller platform by developing features and maintaining existing services.

- Increased the conversion of ShopUp Reseller platform by 50x by developing the ShopUp Reseller mobile application from scratch with React Native, Redux, Firebase, algoliasearch, CleverTap, Branch.IO
- Improved efficiency by 20% by redesigning and developing Product Requisition service which
 helped the inventory and fulfillment team to manage the requisitions and invoices more
 easily. Used: Node, Express, MySQL, React
- Automated all the data collection and verification process for loan applications by building separate mobile applications for portfolio-associates and verification-agents in React Native, Firebase, Redux
- Releasing and managing versions of React Native applications for multiple environments is not a very straight forward approach. I wrote a gradle script along with a npm script to make the process smooth for all 6 mobile applications at ShopUp.
- By developing dashboards for Source Sellers and Key Account Managers, I've managed to push the overall fill-rate to 50% growth of the supply-chain. Used: React.js, Chakra

August 2018 - April 2019 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Fullstack Software Engineer at Ridmik

Ridmik, is a startup who are building different products for local markets of Bangladesh. I was one of their early stage engineers, leading the front-end team of 2 people there.

- Developed a full-fledged rich-text editor in React.js for writing news articles for Ridmik News, which is a news hub product.
- Developed MVP for the BoiToi platform which is a online bookstore based on the local market of Bangladesh. Used: React.js, Redux, Jest
- Created and deployed a separated API service for *Live Cricket Score*, which shows cricket match score update on the Ridmik News mobile application based on the push-notification data message (silent) technology. Used: Python, Flask, Docker, Firebase Cloud Messaging
- One of the major features of Ridmik News mobile application was to show news summaries.
 I created two separate services for scraping news from multiple online news mediums and pass the article text to another service which was responsible for summarizing the article.
 Used: Python, Django, Scrapy, AWS, NLP

March 2018 - June 2018 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Software Engineer Intern at Backpack

Backpack (a Y Combinator-backed startup), is a peer-to-peer platform that connects travelers and shoppers to give people access to products across markets. As an intern, I had the opportunity to learn so many software development techniques e.g. Code reviews, Pair programming, Scrum, Sprint etc. along with the hands on experience of developing and maintaining a service which is in production.

- · Developed careers page of backpack from scratch with React, Redux, Stylus, Node.js, MySQL
- Revamped traveler side of the peer to peer marketplace for better onboarding. Used: React.js

May 2017 - March 2018 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Frontend Developer at Durbin

Durbin, is a startup working on client projects and different SaaS model products. My main role here was to develop UI's for mobile and web applications.

- Developed two mobile applications for clients of Durbin Labs; Hello Doctor and AlEmadi Hospital on React Native, Native Base, Redux and Firebase
- · Developed the MVP of telemedicine and patient management app named DuMedico on React

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

PROJECTS Saloon Gallery (2019)

https://github.com/uraniumreza/bs-rn
https://github.com/uraniumreza/bs-api
https://github.com/uraniumreza/bs-admin
https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.barbersaloon

- An eCommerce platform for local saloons. Saloon owners can buy their stuffs from here.
- Built API services on **Node.js**, **Express**, **MongoDB**; admin panel to manage orders and inventory on **React**, **Redux** and mobile application for users and sales representatives on **React Native**.
- Deployed the api service to Heroku, admin panel to Netlify and mobile application to Google Play-Store

BUET Club (2018)

www.buet.club

A social platform for all the current students and alumni of Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology built on **Django** and **Mysql**

Rezume (2018)

Co-developed a tool to generate resume from beautifully designed templates without any hassle. A fully responsive web-app built on **React**, **Redux** and **Stylus**

Toilet Finder (2018)

https://github.com/uraniumreza/ToiletFinder

A crowd-sourced Toilet Finder mobile app to search nearby public toilet facilities and add new ones to increase the knowledge-base. Used **Firebase** as a no-sql data-storage and **React Native** to build the app. Integrated **google-map api** for the location related services.

PUBLICATIONS

ACM DEV (2016). Towards Making an Anonymous and One-Stop Online Reporting System for Third-World Countries

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, C++, Python, SQL

Frontend Technologies: React, Redux, Stylus, Webpack, Babel, Jest, React-Native

Backend Technologies: Node.js, Express, MySQL

Others: Redis, Docker, Git